what is lorem ipsum a history
you've probably stumbled upon the lorem
ipsum text if you've used some form of
design or web content management
software so where did lorem ipsum come
from is lorem ipsum a person a place
perhaps here's a quick look at its
history lorem ipsum is generally filler
text it's often used in place of text or
visuals in print infographics or web
design its primary purpose is to make
sure that the original text doesn't
distract the designer or developer from
the overall layout and visual hierarchy
think of lorem ipsum as letters acting
as fillers so as not to distract a
person who's working on the visual
layout of a poster website or
infographics
where did lorem ipsum come from the term
lorem ipsum is derived from the latin
term de lorem ipsum which means pain
itself the text has been in use for a
very long time in its history spans for
over two millennia its origins were
discovered by Richard McClintock a Latin
scholar from hampden-sydney College
according to his research lorem ipsum
dates back to 45 BC from classical latin
literature the words in the text
originated from the book de finibus
vanora at malorum translated as the ends
of good and evil the series of books was
a treatise on the theory of ethics and
was written by the ancient Roman
philosopher and statesman Marcus Tullius
Cicero
the placeholder text was taken from the
first books discourse on hedonism the
treatise was very popular during the
Renaissance period and it compelled a
great many intellectuals and luminaries
of the time to read the books but how
did the great works of Cicero who
ultimately become a filler text
according to McClintock it may have just
been a happy coincidence he theorized
that a typesetter
who was required to make a type specimen
book used the text as a way to
demonstrate different fonts with
Cicero's work as one of the most
published works during that time the
typesetter would most likely have used
an excerpt from Cicero's books the
typesetter may have also decided to
scramble the words from a book so as not
to distract himself while working on a
type specimen due to the strange
coincidence the garbled words of a
legendary rhetorician have survived for
over four centuries